{
    "id": "2caed62b1eed443b960be0dbe797891e",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It ………………….. not cost much.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts. It is singular subject. Hence we use does here.",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "do",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… forget to bring the book.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentences.",
            "answers": [
                "Don't",
                "Haven't",
                "Doesn't"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… the door when you leave.",
            "description": "The subject of an imperative sentence is always you hence we use the plural verb close here.",
            "answers": [
                "Close",
                "Closing",
                "Closes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………. faster than anybody I know.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "is running",
                "runs",
                "has run"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He was a true soldier who ………………………….. devoted to the country.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… for a walk every morning.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about our habits and routines.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "will go",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………. to Chennai last month.",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past.",
            "answers": [
                "moved",
                "have moved",
                "had moved"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………… to watch a football match yesterday",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "went",
                "have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Heavy rains ……………………….. the city last week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have flooded",
                "flooded",
                "are flooding"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. him only once.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about life experiences up to now.",
            "answers": [
                "seen",
                "have seen",
                "saw"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Has anyone ……………………… my purse?",
            "description": "We use the third form of the verb after has/have/had.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "saw",
                "seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}